Slocum mss., 1955-2012 LMC 2681
Lilly Library
- VI. Writings (Box 25)
  - The Tangram Book (Box 29)
    - Lewis Carroll (Box 30)
    - Photos and prints (Box 30)
    - Correspondence, (6 folders) (Box 30)
    - Correspondence, David Copperfield (Box 30)
    - Utamaro research, (2 folders) (Box 30)
    - Tangram portrait (Box 30)
    - Dalgety research (Box 30)
    - Ricky Jay (Box 30)
    - Milan text (Box 30)
    - Book list (Box 31)
    - Correspondence (Box 31)
    - Photographs (Box 31)
    - Foreword, by Martin Gardner (Box 31)
    - Author's Draft, 1999 Book Fair (Box 31)
    - Outline (Box 31)
    - Tangram problems, (2 folders) (Box 31)
    - Tangram classification list (Box 31)
    - 15-Piece Puzzle list (Box 31)
    - Napoleon text (Box 31)
    - Tangrams in China (Box 31)
    - Tangram exhibit (Box 31)
    - Research materials (Box 31)
    - Copyright info (Box 31)
    - Page proofs (Box 59)
    - Publicity materials (Box 60)
    - Page proofs, (3 folders) (Box 60)
    - Revised drafts, (4 folders) (Box 60)
  - Puzzles Old & New (Box 28)
    - Notes on text (Box 28)
    - Sales and contract (Box 28)
    - Correspondence, (5 folders) (Box 28)
    - Photo release (Box 28)
    - Corrections (Box 28)
    - Reviews, (2 folders) (Box 28)
    - Book Award materials (Box 28)
    - Draft with edits (Box 28)
    - Page layouts, (2 folders) (Box 58)
  - Magic Mirrors (Box 31)
    - Secret of Chinese Light-Penetration Text (Box 31)
    - Transparent Mirror Text (in Chinese) (Box 31)
    - Patents, bound text (Box 31)
    - Japanese patents (Box 31)
    - Manufacturing methods (Box 31)
    - Bibliography, (2 folders) (Box 31)
    - Reference articles, (3 folders) (Box 31)
    - Drafts, (2 folders) (Box 31)
    - Photographs (Box 31)
    - Research materials (Box 31)
    - Correspondence (Box 31)
    - Kugimiya materials (Box 32)
    - Research files, (3 folders) (Box 32)
    - Correspondence, (2 folders) (Box 32)
    - Operation and test results (Box 32)
    - Contact information (Box 32)
    - Puzzle-knives, (8 folders) (Box 32)
    - Ancient Chinese, master copy, (3 folders) (Box 32)
    - Ancient Japanese, master copy (Box 32)
    - Japanese, master copy (Box 33)
    - Ancient Japanese (Box 33)
    - Japanese (Box 33)
    - Makyoh articles and bibliography (Box 33)
    - Legend of the Knife, Portfolio of Patents (Box 44)
    - Dissertation, psychomotor skills, (2 folders) (Box 44)
    - Patent information on cutlery (Box 44)
    - Articles, books, bibliography, page proofs, (2 volumes) (Box 58)
    - Operation and Test Results, Page Proofs (Box 58)
    - Legend of the Knife, Portfolio of Patents, (2 folders) (Box 60)
    - Cutlery guides, (7 folders) (Box 60)
  - The 15 Puzzle Book (Box 17)
    - Correspondence (Box 17)
    - Keokuk Rebellion (Box 17)
    - U. S. Census, 1870; 1880 (Box 17)
    - Games and toys, Boston, 1881 (Box 17)
    - City directories (Box 17)
    - Chapman family (Box 17)
    - L. Byron Chapman (Box 17)
    - Leibsle Family (Box 17)
    - Horace Chapman (Box 17)
    - Chapman deeds (Box 17)
    - Chapman family census records (Box 17)
    - Wise (Chapman) family (Box 17)
    - Ed Benson Chapman (Box 17)
    - Grace Chapman (Box 17)
    - Helen Chapman (Box 17)
    - Last Will—Anna Belden (Box 17)
    - Summons (Box 17)
    - Madison County Surrogate Court (Box 17)
    - Court cases (Box 17)
    - Book postage (Box 18)
    - Shipping and delivery materials (Box 18)
    - Invoices, (2 folders) (Box 18)
    - Genealogy (Box 18)
    - Princeton (Box 18)
    - Book reviews, (4 folders) (Box 18)
    - Flyers (Box 18)
    - Discount policies (Box 18)
    - General (Box 18)
    - Sales (Box 18)
    - Book sellers (Box 18)
    - Correspondence, (3 folders) (Box 18)
    - Websites (Box 18)
    - Publicity (Box 18)
    - Book orders, (3 folders) (Box 18)
    - Impossibility Proof, articles (Box 33)
    - Bibliography, (2 folders) (Box 33)
    - Literature (Box 33)
    - Research materials A (Box 33)
    - Research materials B (Box 33)
    - Research materials C-D (Box 33)
    - Research materials F (Box 33)
    - Research materials G-H (Box 33)
    - Research materials K (Box 33)
    - Research materials L, (5 folders) (Box 33)
    - Research materials M-R (Box 33)
    - Research materials S, (3 folders) (Box 33)
    - Research materials T (Box 33)
    - Research materials V, (2 folders) (Box 33)
    - Research materials W (Box 33)
    - Inserts (Box 33)
    - Research materials (Box 34)
    - Discrete Mathematics, by Julius Petersen (Box 34)
    - The Embossing Company, by Bill Meridith (Box 34)
    - The 15 Puzzle, drafts #1-5.5 (Box 34)
    - The 15 Puzzle, layout draft (Box 35)
    - The 15 Puzzle, draft #6 (Box 35)
    - Research materials (Box 35)
    - Newspaper indexes (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (AZ) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (CA) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (CT) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (DC) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (GA) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (IA) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (ID) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (IL) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (KS) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (MA) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (MD) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (ME) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (MI) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (MN) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (MO) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (MT) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (ND) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (NJ) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (NV) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (NY), (2 folders) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (OH) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (PA) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (SC) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (TX) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (VA) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (WI) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (WV) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (Canada) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (International) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (deaf-related) (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research Sources (Box 35)
    - Prints (Box 35)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (CO) (Box 36)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (MA), (4 folders) (Box 36)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (MD) (Box 36)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (MN) (Box 36)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (MT) (Box 36)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (NV) (Box 36)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (NY), (6 folders) (Box 36)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (OH) (Box 36)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (OR) (Box 36)
    - Newspaper/Periodical research (PA) (Box 36)
    - Photo lists (Box 36)
    - Manufacturers (Box 36)
    - Bibliography (Box 36)
    - Library search (Box 36)
    - Newspapers lists, (3 folders) (Box 36)
    - Edits (Box 36)
    - Boterman materials (Box 36)
    - Research files (Box 36)
    - Figures list (Box 36)
    - Acknowledgements (Box 36)
    - Book design (Box 36)
    - Newspaper research (CA) (Box 37)
    - Newspaper research (CT) (Box 37)
    - Newspaper research (D.C.) (Box 37)
    - Newspaper research (IL) (Box 37)
    - Newspaper research (KS) (Box 37)
    - Newspaper research (MD) (Box 37)
    - Newspaper research (NY) (Box 37)
    - Newspaper research (PA) (Box 37)
    - Newspaper research (RI) (Box 37)
    - Newspaper research (VT) (Box 37)
    - Periodical research (A-F) (Box 37)
    - Periodical research (G-H) (Box 37)
    - Periodical research (I-O) (Box 37)
    - Periodical research (P-Y) (Box 37)
    - Newspaper and periodical lists (Box 37)
    - Correspondence (Box 37)
    - Research—possible inventors (Box 37)
    - List of cities (19th Century) (Box 37)
    - Advertisements (19th Century) (Box 37)
    - Indexes (Box 37)
    - Research—rewards and solutions (Box 37)
    - Foreword (Will Shortz) (Box 37)
    - Research materials, (2 folders) (Box 37)
    - Draft excerpts (Box 37)
    - Puzzle music, (3 folders) (Box 38)
    - Chronology (Box 38)
    - Research materials (Box 38)
    - Edits (Box 38)
    - Drafts, (2 folders) (Box 38)
    - Research: puzzle insanity (Box 38)
    - Proofs (Box 38)
    - Impact on entertainment (Box 38)
    - Cartoons (Box 38)
    - Poems (Box 38)
    - Humor (Box 38)
    - Metaphors (Box 38)
    - Theater (Box 38)
    - Stories (Box 38)
    - Sales (Box 38)
    - Advertisements in Europe (Box 38)
    - Articles (Box 38)
    - Puzzle Lists (Box 38)
    - Advertisements in United States, (3 folders) (Box 38)
    - International advertisements, (2 folders) (Box 39)
    - Correspondence, (8 folders) (Box 39)
    - Corrections, (3 folders) (Box 39)
    - Supplements (Box 39)
    - Additions (Box 39)
    - Revisions (Box 39)
    - Solutions, (2 folders) (Box 39)
    - Problems (Box 39)
    - Puzzle crazes, (2 folders) (Box 39)
    - Photos, (5 folders) (Box 39)
    - Translations (Box 39)
    - Census records, (2 folders) (Box 39)
    - Gem Puzzle patents (Box 40)
    - Genealogy (Box 40)
    - Puzzle patent documentation (Box 40)
    - Photographs (Box 40)
    - Research materials, (5 folders) (Box 40)
    - Photos, (3 folders) (Box 46)
    - Articles, (2 folders) (Box 46)
    - Correspondence, (2 folders) (Box 46)
    - Education and Instruction of the Deaf and Dumb (19th century) (Box 46)
    - Proofs, (3 folders) (Box 58)
    - Newsclippings (Box 73 (Oversize))
  - The Klutz Puzzle Arcade (Box 43)
    - Solutions, (4 folders) (Box 43)
    - Prices (Box 43)
    - Top 10 puzzles lists (Box 43)
    - Catalogs (Box 43)
    - Puzzle classifications (Box 43)
    - Illustrations, (2 folders) (Box 43)
    - Corrections and suggestions (Box 43)
    - Additions (Box 43)
    - First check draft (Box 43)
    - Final check draft (Box 43)
    - Other drafts (Box 43)
    - The Klutz Puzzle Arcade Prototype, (4 copies) (Box 63)
  - Catel's Cabinet (Box 58)
    - Drafts, (2 folders) (Box 58)
    - Master copy (Box 58)
  - Puzzle Craft (by Stewert T. Coffin) (Box 51)
    - AP-Art, 2003 (Box 51)
    - Design notes 1-52 (Box 51)
    - Design notes 59-100 (Box 51)
    - Puzzle Craft, 1978 (Box 51)
    - Puzzle Craft, 1992 (Box 51)
    - Puzzle Craft, 1985 (Box 51)
    - The Puzzling World..., 1987 (Box 51)
    - The Puzzling World..., 1990 (Box 51)
    - Puzzle Craft, 2006 (Box 51)
    - Tall Trees and Wild Bees, 2005 (Box 51)
    - Design notes 200-240 (Box 52)
    - AP-ART Puzzle List and Design Notes (Box 52)
    - Design Notes 102-199 (Box 52)
    - Puzzle List 1-227 (Box 52)
    - Page proofs for various manuscripts (Box 71 (Oversize))
    - Page proofs for various manuscripts (Box 82 (Oversize))
    - Page proofs for various manuscripts (Box 84 (Oversize))
- VII. Patents, Photocopies (Box 20)
  Numeric sequence reflects chronological order of puzzle patent approvals from 1849-1989.
  - #0—99,000 (Box 20)
  - #100,000—199,000 (Box 20)
  - #200,000—299,000 (Box 20)
  - #300,000—399,000 (Box 20)
  - #400,000—499,000, (2 folders) (Box 20)
  - #500,000—599,000, (2 folders) (Box 20)
  - #600,000—699,000 (Box 20)
  - #700,000—799,000 (Box 21)
  - #800,000—899,000 (Box 21)
  - #900,000—999,000 (Box 21)
  - #1,000,000—1,099,000 (Box 21)
  - #1,100,000—1,199,000 (Box 21)
  - #1,200,000—1,299,000 (Box 21)
  - #1,300,000—1,399,000 (Box 21)
  - #1,400,000—1,499,000 (Box 21)
  - #1,500,000—1,599,000 (Box 21)
  - #1,600,000—1,699,000 (Box 21)
  - #1,700,000--1,799,000 (Box 21)
  - #1,800,000—1,899,000 (Box 21)
  - #1,900,000—1,999,000 (Box 21)
  - #2,000,000—2,099,000 (Box 21)
  - #2,100,000—2,199,000 (Box 21)
  - #2,200,000—2,299,000 (Box 21)
  - #2,300,000—2,399,000 (Box 21)
  - #2,400,000—2,499,000 (Box 21)
  - #2,500,000—2,599,000 (Box 21)
  - #2,600,000—2,699,000 (Box 21)
  - #2,700,000—2,799,000 (Box 21)
  - #2,800,000—2,899,000 (Box 21)
  - #2,900,000—2,999,000 (Box 21)
  - #3,000,000—3,099,000 (Box 21)
  - #3,100,000—3,199,000 (Box 21)
  - #3,200,000—3,299,000 (Box 21)
  - #3,300,000—3,399,000 (Box 21)
  - #3,400,000—3,499,000 (Box 22)
  - #3,500,000—3,599,000 (Box 22)
  - #3,600,000—3,699,000 (Box 22)
  - #3,700,000—3,799,000 (Box 22)
  - #3,800,000—3,899,000 (Box 22)
  - #3,900,000—3,999,000 (Box 22)
  - #4,000,000—4,099,000 (Box 22)
  - #4,300,000—4,900,000 (Box 22)
  - Other patents (Box 22)
  - Civil Suit: Paul Gallant v. Telebrands, (3 folders) (Box 22)
  - Puzzle patent lists, (5 folders) (Box 45)
  - NARA research (Box 45)
  - Copyright research (Box 45)
  - Puzzle trademarks (Box 45)
  - British registered design patents, (2 folders) (Box 45)
  - Patents—to order (Box 45)
  - Classifications (Box 45)
  - Registered designs (Box 45)
  - European patents (Box 45)
  - United States Patent Padlocks (Box 45)
  - Patent description list (Box 46)
  - 3-D jigsaw puzzles (Box 58)
- VIII. Directories (Box 22)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes puzzle makers, suppliers, publishers, and collectors.
  - CD-ROM: cover of 2000 Directory (Box 22)
  - Publicity materials (Box 22)
  - Directory, 2nd ed., 1994 (Box 22)
  - Directory, 3rd ed., 1997 (Box 22)
  - Questionnaire, A-B (Box 22)
  - Questionnaire, C-E (Box 22)
  - Questionnaire, F-G (Box 22)
  - Questionnaire, H-J (Box 22)
  - Questionnaire, K-L (Box 22)
  - Questionnaire, M-O (Box 22)
  - Questionnaire, P-R (Box 22)
  - Questionnaire, S-T (Box 22)
  - Questionnaire, U-Z (Box 23)
  - Questionnaire, miscellaneous (Box 23)
  - Correspondence, (4 folders) (Box 23)
  - Orders, (2 folders) (Box 23)
  - Master copy, (3 folders) (Box 23)
  - Costs and income (Box 23)
  - Completed inputs, (2 folders) (Box 23)
  - Forms (Box 23)
  - Collectors, A-G (Box 23)
  - Collectors, H-O (Box 23)
  - Collectors, P-Z (Box 23)
  - Rental stores and sellers (Box 24)
  - Questionnaire, mailing envelopes (Box 24)
  - Questionnaire, mailing list (Box 24)
  - Questionnaire, puzzle sellers (Box 24)
  - Questionnaire, rental stores (Box 24)
  - Photographs (Box 24)
  - Directory of Puzzle Collectors & Puzzle Sellers, Master Copy for printing, (2 folders) (Box 58)
- XI. Rubik's Cube Trial (Box 47)
  Materials from the 1982 patent infringement suit filed by Moleculon Research Corporation on behalf of Larry Nichols, against Ideal Toy Company, in which it claimed that Ideal Toy had violated Nichols's 1972 patent with the release of Erno Rubik's 1974 patented cube.
  - Gustafson deposition – Copy 2, Sept. 1, 1982 (Box 47)
  - Gustafson depositionPart I, Dec. 1983 (Box 47)
  - Gustafson depositionPart II, Dec. 1983 (Box 47)
  - Gustafson patent, application, and correspondence (Box 47)
  - Nichols patent (Box 48)
  - Rubik patent (Box 48)
  - Rubik patent – non-English (Box 48)
  - Other puzzle patents (Box 48)
  - Nichols patent – references and notes (Box 48)
  - Rubik's Cube history – notes (Box 48)
  - History of puzzles – patents and inventors (Box 48)
  - Frank Fox patents with notes (Box 48)
  - Trial correspondence (Box 48)
  - Meeting notes (Box 48)
  - Testimony notes (Box 48)
  - Trial articles – originals and copies (Box 48)
  - Souvenirs (Box 48)
  - Nichols deposition (Box 48)
  - Nichols patent application – drafts and notes (Box 48)
  - Correspondence between W. Brown Morten, Jr. and William O. Gustafson (Box 48)
  - Rubik deposition (Box 49)
  - Slocum deposition (Box 49)
  - Complaint and opinion (Box 49)
  - Trial transcript – day 1 (Box 49)
  - Trial transcript – day 4 (Box 49)
  - Trial transcript – day 5 (Box 49)
  - Trial transcript – day 6 (Box 49)
  - Trial transcript – day 7 (Box 49)
  - Trial transcript – day 8 (Box 49)
  - Defendant post-trial brief (Box 49)
  - Plaintiff post-trial brief (Box 49)
  - Plaintiff's reply to brief (Box 49)
  - First Lower Court opinion (Box 49)
  - Memo opposing motion for new trial (Box 49)
  - Brief for Appelle (Box 49)
  - CBS Appellate brief (Box 49)
  - First Appellate opinion (Box 49)
  - Memo about First Appellate opinion (Box 49)
  - Second brief for Appelle (Box 49)
  - Second Lower Court opinion (Box 49)
  - Second Appellate opinion (Box 49)
  - Petition for rehearing (Box 49)
  - Trial transcript – Day 2 (Box 52)
  - Trial transcript – Day 3 (Box 52)
- X. Puzzle Descriptions (Box 52)
  - Index card Box 1: business cards (Box 52)
  - Index card Box 2: puzzle collector and maker information (Box 52)
  - Index card Box 1: individual puzzle descriptions, 1.1-2.1 (Box 53)
  - Index card Box 2: individual puzzle descriptions, 2.2-3.4 (Box 53)
  - Index card Box 1: individual puzzle descriptions, 3.5-5.2 (Box 54)
  - Index card Box 2: individual puzzle descriptions, 5.3-6.3 (Box 54)
  - Index card Box 1: individual puzzle descriptions, 6.4-7.6 (Box 55)
  - Index card Box 2: exhibition puzzle descriptions, Part I (Box 55)
  - Index card Box 1: exhibition puzzle descriptions, part II (Box 56)
  - Index card Box 2: exhibition puzzle descriptions, part III (Box 56)
  - Index card Box 1: exhibition puzzle descriptions, part IV (Box 57)
  - Index card Box 2: other puzzle descriptions (Box 57)
- XI. Education (Box 45)
  - Denkspiele im Klassenzimmer (Box 45)
  - AIMS Catalogs and Publications (Box 45)
  - Surveys—Puzzles in Schools (Box 45)
  - Correspondence—Puzzles in Schools, (2 folders) (Box 45)
  - Teacher's Guides, (2 folders) (Box 45)
  - Survey, (3 folders) (Box 46)
  - Recommendations (Box 46)
  - Mechanical puzzles exhibition, 2002 (Box 46)
  - Bunchgrass Folk Toys, catalogs (Box 46)
  - Channel Craft, catalog (Box 46)
  - Puzzles for Schools, (3 folders) (Box 46)
  - Programs (Box 46)
  - Articles, (2 folders) (Box 46)
  - Booklets (Box 46)
  - Textbook: Exploring Math through Puzzles, by Wei Zhang (Box 46)
  - Tangram learning studies (Box 46)
  - Thesis: The Effect of a Puzzle Unit on the Achievement of Algebra I Students, by C. L. Sanders (Box 46)
  - Educational Materials K-8, catalog (Box 46)
  - Bibliography (Box 46)
  - Presentations (Box 46)
- XII. Photographs (Box 69)
  - Photos of Jerry Slocum (Box 69)
  - Puzzle people (Box 69)
  - 15 puzzle (Box 69)
  - Mechanical puzzles, (3 folders) (Box 69)
  - Checkerboard puzzles, (5 folders) (Box 69)
  - Ingenious and Diabolical Puzzles (Box 69)
  - Klutz Puzzle Arcade (Box 69)
  - Puzzle collections, (3 folders) (Box 69)
  - Tangrams, (4 folders) (Box 69)
  - Wood puzzles, (2 folders) (Box 69)
  - GM Hughes Aircraft, (2 folders) (Box 69)
- XIII. Audio-visual (Box 67)
  - VHS tapes (Box 67)
    - Johnny Carson:, 10/10/1986 (Box 67)
    - Johnny Carson, last 6 minutes:, 10/10/1986 (Box 67)
    - Puzzles on Discovery:, November 8, 1994 (Box 67)
    - ABC Network News, Nov. 28; (no date) (Box 67)
    - ABC News, Collections and Puzzle Outtakes, Nov. 1994 (Box 67)
    - ABC News: Collections and Outtakes (Box 67)
    - Puzzles on ABC News, Nov. 1994 (Box 67)
    - Discovery: Puzzle Man, Nov. 1994 (Box 67)
    - Discovery and ABC News Specials (Box 67)
    - Discovery, Nov. 8, 1994 (Box 67)
    - Slocum on TV: Discovery, HGTV What's Your Hobby?, ABC News (Box 67)
    - Gerry Slocum, Business World (Box 67)
    - Jerry Slocum's Puzzle Show, 1996 (Box 67)
    - Slocum Family Movies, 3 tapes, n.d. (Box 67)
    - Jerry Slocum's Puzzles (Box 67)
    - David L. Disney, Puzzle Enthusiast (Box 67)
    - From the Kleine Collection in the Library of Congress (Box 67)
    - Max Maven's Mindgames (Box 67)
    - Puzzle Masters, Corporate Sponsorship Promo (Box 67)
    - Termespheres (Box 67)
    - Erik & Dad Puzzle co. (Box 67)
    - Secrets of Magic 1 and 2 (Box 67)
    - Berrocal (Box 67)
    - Pieces of Time, Fresno Metropolitan Museum, January 1992-February 1994 (Box 67)
    - A Puzzle Trio (Box 67)
    - Peter Beck Cube Collection (Box 67)
    - Laurel and Hardy Classic Collection (Box 67)
    - Fun & Games: British TV Puzzle Series (Box 67)
    - Watch Your Language (Box 67)
    - Magic Secrets Revealed #3 (Box 67)
    - Puzzle Masters (Box 67)
    - Mongolian Museum, 2001 (Box 67)
    - Mongolia Museum (Box 67)
    - Unidentified title (possibly in Mandarin) (Box 67)
    - Tom Lensch: American Woodwork (Box 67)
    - Harry Eng Lecture (Box 67)
    - Toyo Glass, (2 tapes) (Box 67)
    - Atlanta Dinnershow (Box 67)
  - Reel-to-reel tape (Box 67)
    - Tangram (Box 67)
  - Audio cassettes (Box 68)
    - Puzzle Party, 1986 (Box 68)
    - NOB Puzzle Lecture, 1987 (Box 68)
    - International Intellectual Museum (Box 68)
    - Stewart Coffin, 2000 (Box 68)
    - Wirt Puzzles (Box 68)
    - CKNW, 1998 (Box 68)
    - Puzzle Interview, 1984 (Box 68)
    - Italian Book Translation (Box 68)
    - Hughes Aircraft, mini-cassette with audio recorder (Box 68)
  - Floppy computer disks (Box 68)
    - Sliding-Block Puzzle, (2) (Box 68)
    - Magno's Bug House (Box 68)
    - Franco's Bug House (Box 68)
    - TIFF-PC, (6) (Box 68)
    - AIMS (Box 68)
    - From NOB (Box 68)
    - C&B, edited (Box 68)
    - Holger Larsen, Mandarinen (Box 68)
  - CD-ROMS (Box 68)
    - Complete Stewart Coffin (Box 68)
    - Puzzle-Eye (from NOB), (2) (Box 68)
    - NOB's articles, columns and photos (Box 68)
    - Puzzletopia, by NOB (Box 68)
    - NOB's Sales Pitch, 2003 (Box 68)
    - AGPC, from NOB (Box 68)
    - Puzzle Patent List, Jerry Slocum, 2009 (Box 68)
    - HSBC Fortune Global Forum video reference (Box 68)
    - Carlson's Icosahedron: The Ultimate Scramble-Unscramble Puzzle (Box 68)
    - Cover: Directory of Puzzle Collections (Box 68)
    - Directory 5: PDF Files, 2003; (2) (Box 68)
    - The Popular 15 Puzzle (Box 68)
    - Puzzle 15 Song, recorded June 10, 2005 (Box 68)
    - 15 Puzzle Book, proof and corrections (Box 68)
    - Online Ads: Tangram, 2005 (Box 68)
    - HSBC Tangram Ads, October 2005; (3) (Box 68)
    - HRDE, Study (Box 68)
  - Other A/V (Box 68)
    - Casio IC Card (Box 68)
    - Hard drive, mechanical puzzle designs by Oskar van Deventer (Box 68)
  - Microfilm (Box 80)
    - Narragansett Weekly:, September 13, 1877—September 8, 1881; (2 copies) (Box 80)
    - Canastota Herald:, September 3, 1879—August 24, 1881 (Box 80)
    - Syracuse Daily Courier Newspaper:, January 1, 1880—June 30, 1880 (Box 80)
    - Syracuse Daily Journal:, January 2, 1880—June 30, 1880 (Box 80)
    - Syracuse Morning Standard:, February 5, 1880—August 21, 1880 (Box 80)
    - Syracuse Evening Herald:, January 2, 1879—April 20, 1880 (Box 80)
- XIV. Articles (Box 79 (Oversize))
  - Articles on Slocum (Box 79 (Oversize))
  - Articles on puzzle collectors (Box 8 (Oversize)6)
  - Articles on puzzles (Box 96 (Oversize))
- XV. Artwork (Box 81 (Oversize))
  - Portrait of Jerry Slocum (Box 81 (Oversize))
  - Cover art (Box 105 (Oversize))
- XVI. Biographical (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Signed card for Jerry Slocum (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Degrees (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Broadside with factoids (Box 82 (Oversize))
- XVII. Posters (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Puzzle posters (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Puzzle posters (Box 83 (Oversize))
  - Puzzle posters (Box 97 (Oversize))
  - Impossible puzzle/Escher posters (Box 98 (Oversize))
  - Puzzle posters (Box 99 (Oversize))
  - Puzzle posters (Box 100 (Oversize))
  - CAFM exhibition posters (Box 101 (Oversize))
  - Puzzle posters (Box 102 (Oversize))
  - Maze posters and puzzle posters (Box 103 (Oversize))
  - Puzzle posters (Box 104 (Oversize))
  - CAFM exhibition posters (Box 106 (Oversize))
  - Japan exhibition posters (Box 107 (Oversize))
  - Puzzle posters (Box 108 (Oversize))
- XVIII. Exhibitions (Box 89)
  - Handouts (Box 89)
  - Handouts (Box 90)
- XIX. Miscellaneous Puzzle-related Materials (Box 83 (Oversize))
  - Charts (Box 83 (Oversize))
  - Broadsides (Box 83 (Oversize))
  - Ephemera (Box 83 (Oversize))
  - Newsclippings, 1984-2009; (2 folders) (Box 93)
  - Newsclippings, print-outs of online newspapers, (2 folders) (Box 93)
  - Newsclippings, 19th century (Box 93)
  - Correspondence, 1998-2009 (Box 93)
  - Ephemera, undated (Box 93)